The Gray Man is a action, thriller film directed by Joe Russo.
When a shadowy CIA agent uncovers damning agency secrets, he's hunted across the
globe by a sociopathic rogue operative who's put a bounty on his head.
Six, played by Ryan Gosling.
Lloyd Hansen, played by Chris Evans.
Dani Miranda, played by Ana de Armas.
Fitzroy, played by Billy Bob Thornton.
Suzanne Brewer, played by Jessica Henwick.
Avik San, played by Dhanush.
The Gray Man is a 2022 American action thriller film directed by Anthony and Joe Russo, from a screenplay Joe Russo
co-wrote with Christopher Markus and Stephen McFeely, based on the 2009 novel of the same name by Mark Greaney.
The film stars Ryan Gosling, Chris Evans, Ana de Armas, Jessica Henwick, Regé-Jean Page, Wagner Moura,
Julia Butters, Dhanush (in his Hollywood debut), Alfre Woodard, and Billy Bob Thornton.
Produced by the Russo brothers' company AGBO, it is the first film in
a franchise based upon Greaney's  Gray Man novels.
The plot centers on CIA agent "Sierra Six" (portrayed by Gosling), who is on the run from sociopathic ex-CIA
agent and mercenary Lloyd Hansen (Evans) upon discovering corrupt secrets about his superior.
An adaptation of Greaney's novel was originally announced in 2011, with James Gray set to direct Brad Pitt, and
later Charlize Theron in a gender-swapped role, though neither version ever came to fruition.
The property lingered in development hell until July 2020, when it was announced the
Russo brothers would direct, with both Gosling and Evans attached to star.
Filming took place in Los Angeles, Paris and Prague between March and July 2021.
With a production budget of $200 million, it is among
the most expensive films made by Netflix.
The Gray Man began a limited theatrical release on July 15, 2022,
followed by its digital release on Netflix on July 22, 2022.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for the ensemble cast and action sequences, but criticism toward the "clichéd script and
breakneck pacing." The film is being followed by a sequel, with Gosling and Dhanush reprising their roles, as well as a spin-off.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia),
based on novel or book, hitman, kidnapping, agent.
The tone is intense.